now that we know how caches find data
when we are looking for it let's talk
about what happens when we need to
replace something from the cache to make
room for new data because we have a miss
so the situation when we need
replacement is the set where the data
needs to go is full we have a miss so we
need somewhere to put the new block that
we're bringing in and we need to put it
in that set and the question for cach
replacement is which of the blocks in
the set do we kick out to make room for
the new one possible replacement
policies are random just pick a block
randomly from those that are already in
the set fifo which kicks out the block
that has been there the longest so in
fifo let's say we have two blocks we
bring in a then we bring B when we want
to bring in C we're going to kick out a
because it's been there the longest then
we're going to kick out B to bring
and so on the next policy is lru or
least recently used we want to kick out
the block that has not been used the
longest so we definitely don't want to
kick out the block that is the most
recently used and then the next most
recently used and so on so pretty much
we track which block has been used more
recently and when we need to replace
something we choose the block that we
haven't used for the longest time it
turns out that lru is a really good
policy so there are several policies
that are trying to approximate it
because this is not easy to do one such
policy for example is NMU or not most
recently used which tracks just which
block has been used the most recently
and then picks randomly among the
remaining blocks so pretty much don't
pick the block that was just used